<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>LofFiNet</title>
    <link href="https://hyakugei.github.io/LoFiNet-Blog/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://hyakugei.github.io/LoFiNet-Blog" />
    <updated>2025-11-22T15:38:27-05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Jos</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://hyakugei.github.io/LoFiNet-Blog</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Code and Death</title>
        <author>
            <name>Jos</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://hyakugei.github.io/LoFiNet-Blog/code-and-death.html"/>
        <id>https://hyakugei.github.io/LoFiNet-Blog/code-and-death.html</id>

        <updated>2025-11-22T15:38:27-05:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                    Working on some basic "next steps" for the combat system. When implementing the stagger stuff i had to revisit the frame animation system i wrote for this game (more details later). Specifically i had to add a .durationMultiplier, so i could simply extend the basic&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Working on some basic "next steps" for the combat system. </p>
<ol>
<li>Action Lock and Rotation Lock while attacking</li>
<li>Attack Cooldowns</li>
<li>Mini-Stagger when hit (action lock, slowed movement)</li>
<li>HP &amp; Death</li>
</ol>
<p>When implementing the stagger stuff i had to revisit the frame animation system i wrote for this game (more details later). Specifically i had to add a <code>.durationMultiplier</code>, so i could simply extend the basic animations, and slow them down... Or i guess also speed them up. Anyway, that took a bit of futzing to get working corretly, now needing the frame accumulator to work with floats rather then the simple ints. Sigh. Stagger is kind of complicated because I also want any "in progress" actions (attacks, jump, roll, etc) to finish out before applying the stagger effects. </p>
<p>Finally added HP and damage values (very basic, <code>JabDamage</code> and <code>SlashDamage</code>just to get something in there quick). And the <strong>Death</strong> state/animation. Sweet. </p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://hyakugei.github.io/LoFiNet-Blog/media/posts/5/2025-11-22_15-30.gif" alt="" width="270" height="196"></figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Blocked</title>
        <author>
            <name>Jos</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://hyakugei.github.io/LoFiNet-Blog/blocked.html"/>
        <id>https://hyakugei.github.io/LoFiNet-Blog/blocked.html</id>

        <updated>2025-11-20T22:30:48-05:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                    Just fooling around trying to get the github pages and the custom url/dns to all play nice together, so i can publish this blog. I added some logic that checks when you are hit, if you are facing the entity that hit you, and if&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Just fooling around trying to get the github pages and the custom url/dns to all play nice together, so i can publish this blog. </p>
<p>I added some logic that checks when you are hit, if you are facing the entity that hit you, and if you are holding down the BLOCK input. If so, then you would have... blocked... the attack? Right now it just puts out a different debug log. But that is, now, a fully "functioning" combat system! Sorta. With no HP. Or reactions. </p>
<p>Oh, i also made the players/entities non-interactive, from the POV of their own colliders/physics, so you can now just pass-though another entity. Eventually there will be non-player entities which will block you, but for now, this is how i want it. </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Combat-ish</title>
        <author>
            <name>Jos</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://hyakugei.github.io/LoFiNet-Blog/combat-ish.html"/>
        <id>https://hyakugei.github.io/LoFiNet-Blog/combat-ish.html</id>

        <updated>2025-11-19T21:48:42-05:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                    Ok, had to fix up the new HFSM -- the builder didn't have a "root" node by default, so my AnyStates &amp; Transitions were not properly firing. That is now fixed, and the Block animation is now working. Ok, now have a `AttackHitboxController`, which is&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Ok, had to fix up the new HFSM -- the builder didn't have a "root" node by default, so my AnyStates &amp; Transitions were not properly firing. That is now fixed, and the Block animation is now working. </p>
<p><br>Ok, now have a `AttackHitboxController`, which is turning on/off the hit box and doing the `Physics.OverlapBox()` checks for other Entities. Had to revamp how i was flipping the visuals, so that not just the character-visuals game object was having its localScale.x * -1 for left, but also the combat game object, which will be dealing with hit boxes and hurt-boxes too (at some point). Anyway, these are now in a list of `Transforms` which need to be switched/flipped, if i ever have more... Turns out, box colliders do not like scale -1, so i actually now manually move the hit-box center when the player "flips" left to right. I added an event that things can subscribe to when that happens (in the Entity). <br><br>So, wow, i now have some simple "combat" like behaviour -- i really need to put in some kind of other damageable thing, so i can test without multiplayer... and maybe not look for a specific other ENTITY, but some `IDamageable` interface or something.</p>
<p>I should also note that this is local only, in that the local client is determining hits. Eventually, the server will be the source of truth for this kind of combat stuff, but i wanted to get something running quick, so i could see if the hit stuff was working. </p>
<p>This first gif shows the swing and hit, via a log in the console (very exciting).<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://hyakugei.github.io/LoFiNet-Blog/media/posts/3/2025-11-19_21-41.gif" alt="" width="970" height="720"></figure>
<p>Ok and this second gif shows 2 clients (and the server) so you can see that they are actually networked. <figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://hyakugei.github.io/LoFiNet-Blog/media/posts/3/2025-11-19_21-45.gif" alt="" width="970" height="720"></figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Obligitory First Post</title>
        <author>
            <name>Jos</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://hyakugei.github.io/LoFiNet-Blog/obligitory-first-post.html"/>
        <id>https://hyakugei.github.io/LoFiNet-Blog/obligitory-first-post.html</id>

        <updated>2025-11-19T10:04:37-05:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                    I'm going to document the development of this game, LoFiNet: Alpha. Quickly at a high level: In order to be a bit different (haha, 18.5k games released last year on steam) from many other online pixel/voxel games, I'm going to be intially concentrating on a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>I'm going to document the development of this game, LoFiNet: Alpha. Quickly at a high level:</p>
<ul>
<li>Online Multiplayer with a hosted Server</li>
<li>Persistant Voxel-ish 3D World</li>
<li>Top Down Isometric camera</li>
<li>2D sprite based characters</li>
<li>Not Minecraft, Stardew Valley or Animal Crossing
<ul>
<li>Although i hope to add <em>some</em> features from all those, eventually.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>In order to be a bit different (haha, <a href="https://steamdb.info/stats/releases/">18.5k games released last year on steam</a>) from many other online pixel/voxel games, I'm going to be intially concentrating on a skill based, lag-tolerant, press your luck PvP combat system. These will be 1 on 1 duels that players enter into by choice. </p>
<p>Here is a gif of some movement, running on a client connected to the server. </p>
<figure class="post__image align-left"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://hyakugei.github.io/LoFiNet-Blog/media/posts/2/ShortClip_480.gif" alt="" width="320" height="258"></figure>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
